bdm.qld.gov.au 2013-12-21

# Privacy and security - Department of Justice and Attorney-General

## Your privacy

The Department of Justice and Attorney-General is committed to protecting user privacy. Like other Queensland public sector agencies, the department is required to comply with eleven (11) Information Privacy Principles (IPPs) contained in the [Information Privacy Act 2009](http://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/LEGISLTN/CURRENT/I/InfoPrivA09.pdf), (IPS Act) that set out how personal information must be collected and managed in the public sector environment.

Back to top

## Cookies

This website uses cookies to collect information about our visitors and to track advertising campaign data. A 'cookie' is a small file that is sent to your computer when you visit our website. When you visit our website again, the cookie provides us with information about your interactions within our website. Cookies may store user preferences and other information. You can set your browser to refuse cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some of our website features or services may not function properly without cookies.

Back to top

## Information collected

Unless you specifically tell us, the department will not know who you are.

Any personal information you provide will be used for the purpose specified at the time it is collected, and will otherwise be managed in accordance with the IP Act. If you are advising of a health and safety or electrical safety [reportable incident](http://www.justice.qld.gov.au/fair-and-safe-work/electrical-safety/incident-notification) the department may be required by law to disclose personal information to other government agencies or entities as required.

When you visit the department's web site, our web servers make a record of your visit and records anonymous information for statistical purposes only. This information is:

  * the type of browser, computer platform and screen resolution you are using 
  * your traffic patterns through our site such as: 
    * the date and time of your visit to the site 
    * the pages you accessed and documents downloaded 
    * the previous page you visited prior to accessing our site 
  * the Internet address of the server accessing our site 

This information will only be made available to the Department of Justice and Attorney-General.

No attempt will be made to identify your personal details unless we are legally required to do so.

Back to top

## Email

As this is a Queensland Government web site, email correspondence sent to this site will be treated as a public record and will be retained as required by the [Public Records Act 2002](http://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/LEGISLTN/CURRENT/P/PublicRecA02.pdf) and other relevant regulations.

Your name and address will not be added to a mailing list and we will not disclose these details to third parties without your consent, unless required by law. However, email messages may be monitored by authorised IT staff for purposes such as system troubleshooting and maintenance.

We will disclose your email details to the relevant authorities if necessary to protect the safety of the public or to protect the rights and property of the State of Queensland.

Back to top

## Security

This site does not provide open access facilities for securely transmitting information across the Internet. You are advised that there can be risks with transmitting information across the Internet.

This site may contain links to non-Queensland Government websites. The Department is not responsible for the privacy or security practices or the content of such websites.

Back to top

## Access to your information

The [Right to Information Act 2009](http://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/LEGISLTN/CURRENT/R/RightInfoA09.pdf) (the RTI Act) and the [Information Privacy Act 2009](http://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/LEGISLTN/CURRENT/I/InfoPrivA09.pdf) (the IP Act) give a right of access to information held by government (including documents held by the department), unless, on balance it would be contrary to the public interest to release the information.

If you wish to make a formal application, you can apply with the [Smart Service Queensland's Right to Information application form](https://www.smartservice.qld.gov.au/services/information-requests/apply.action) for access under the RTI Act or IP Act to information held by Queensland Government departments and Ministers.

Alternatively, you can download the [Right to Information and Information Privacy Access Application (PDF, 171.5 KB)](http://www.justice.qld.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0005/133277/RTI-Access-App-form.pdf) and submit your application via post, fax or email or in person. You will need to submit your application this way if you wish to apply to agencies other than Queensland Government departments or Ministers.

It helps if you provide as much information as possible about the document you are seeking. If you know the title, subject matter, agency reference number, type of document or the date it was produced, please specify these details in your application.

If your application is for non-personal information, you will pay a $41.90 application fee and processing and access charges may apply.

You can also submit a [Information Privacy Personal Information Amendment Application](http://www.rti.qld.gov.au/accessing-government-information/personal-information-amendment) under the IP Act if you believe the information is inaccurate, incomplete, out of date or misleading.

Back to top
